[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：作为对任何可能通过视频或视频加入我们的人的快速介绍
&gt;&gt; Kyle: As quick intro for anyone that maybe joining us on video or
一个以前没听说过我的人，简单介绍一下，
someone that hasn't heard of me before, just a quick intro,
我的名字是凯尔辛普森，被称为getify。
my name is Kyle Simpson known as getify.
我可以在所有主要的地方找到getify，比如Twitter和
And I can be found getify at all the major places like Twitter and
GitHub，Gmail所有其他地方我列出这些东西是因为我鼓励你
GitHub, Gmail all those other places I list this stuff because I encourage you
联系并提供反馈或提出问题。
to reach out and provide feedback or ask questions.
回顾那些东西，特别是将要经历的东西
Be going back over the stuff particularly the stuff that will be going through
在这个研讨会的过程中，这里有很多的深度，特别是
through the course of this workshop and there's a lot of depth here especially
随着我们深入其中，练习变得极具挑战性。
as we get further into it it's the exercises become extremely challenging.
有一些练习花了我几周的时间去锻炼，而且
There are exercises that took me weeks to work out, and
那我希望你在20分钟内完成
then I'm expecting you to do them in 20 minutes.
所以他们故意极具挑战性。
So they're extremely challenging on purpose.
我只是试图推动您对异步模式的理解。
I'm just trying to push your understanding of asynchronous patterns.
所以如果你对此有疑问或者你在挣扎，
So if you have questions about that or if you're struggling with that,
请随时联系。
please feel free to reach out.
我很乐意帮你
I'd love to help you with that.
很快，我做了几个开源项目，
Just real quickly, I've done several open source projects,
LABjs，脚本加载器，夹点作为模板引擎，异步。
LABjs, script loader, grips as a templating engine, asynquence.
实际上，我们会花很多时间讨论异步。
We're gonna spend a lot of time talking about asynquence actually.
但不是因为我想把图书馆卖给你，
But not because I'm trying to sell you on that library,
原因很简单，因为它的设计目的是帮助使异步编程概念变得更容易
simply because it is designed to help make asynchronous programming concepts easier
在你的大脑中理解和管理是为了让它们更容易教。
to understand and manage in your brain is designed to make them easier to teach.
因此，当我们在整个研讨会中进行时，您会接触到一些不同步现象。
So you get some exposure to asynquences as we go throughout this workshop.
我是Maker Square的课程主管
I am the head of curriculum for Maker Square for
在过去的三四个月里。
about the last three or four months.
Maker Square是一所开发工程师培训学校。
Maker Square is a developer engineer training school.
我们在奥斯汀、旧金山和洛杉矶设有校园，而且
We have campuses in Austin, San Francisco, and Los Angeles, and
我们也将扩张。
we will be expanding, as well.
我们把你从初级状态带到中级状态，
We take you from junior level status to intermediate status,
这与其他学校略有不同。
and that's slightly different than other schools.
这可能会说，我们从无到有，让你进入初级水平
Which may say, we start you from nothing and get you to junior level status for
更高端的，
more on the higher end,
我们更喜欢把自己想象成这些开发学校中的麻省理工学院。
we like to kind of think of ourselves more like the MIT of these developer schools.
所以你从更高的水平开始，这更符合你的要求，但是
So you start out at a higher level, it's more as required of you but
我们还将带您更深入地了解完整堆栈JavaScript学校，因此
we also take you a lot further to Full-Stack JavaScript school so
我们教所有的前端框架，比如角度和反应
we teach all the front end Frameworks like the angulars and reacts and
所有后端的东西，像Mongo，Node和Express等诸如此类的东西。
all the backend things like Mongo and Node and Express and things like that.
[咳嗽]如果你有任何问题或
[COUGH] If you have any questions or
关于科技学校的想法，或者你知道有人对此感兴趣或有一些
thoughts about tech schooling or you know somebody that's interested or has some
如果有问题，请把他们和我联系，我很想和你多聊聊这个。
questions please put them in touch with me I'd love to chat with you more about that.
我写了一系列关于JavaScript的书，名为“你不知道JS”(You Don‘t Know JS)。
I've written a series of books on JavaScript called You Don't Know JS.
我们今天要讨论的很多内容都是以某种形式或
A lot of what we're gonna talk about today is covered in some way shape or
那些书里的形式。
form in those books.
特别是异步和性能书籍，以及ES6书籍。
Particularly, the Async and Performance book, as well as the ES6 book.
您应该能够找到其中一些主题的相当多的覆盖范围
You should be able to find quite a bit of coverage of some of these topics
在那些书里。
in those books.
整个6本书系列价值1100页，可以在GitHub在线免费获得。
The entire 6 book series 1,100 pages worth is available for free online at GitHub.
你不知道js.com会重定向到那个地方。
You don't know js.com will redirect to that.
您也可以购买它们。
You can also purchase them.
他们已经通过O‘Reilly编辑和出版了。
They've been edited and published through O'Reilly.
所以，如果你对这些内容感到满意，你可以购买它们。
So you can purchase them if you're happy with that content.
今天，我们将讨论异步模式。
Today, we are going to talk about asynchronous patterns.
现在，我想马上解释一下我对这件事的态度，
Now, I wanna explain right off the bat that my approach to this,
就像我教的其他东西一样，
much like my approach to the other things that I teach,
在解释如何使用某物之前，首先要关注这个概念。
is to first focus on the concept before explaining the how to use something.
这与我的一些同龄人不同，他们是第一个
That differs from some of my peers who were first
会向你展示某样东西的API
would present to you the API for something and
然后也许稍后，你可能会了解它背后的一些概念。
then maybe perhaps later, you might pick up on some of the conceptuals behind it.
我认为对你来说更有效的是理解你为什么做某件事
I think it's more effective for you to understand why you do something a certain
在真正沉浸于实际做的事情之前就已经有很长的路要走了。
way before actually getting too immersed in the actual doing of the thing.
所以举个例子，
So for example,
你们中的一些人可能已经对承诺有些熟悉了。
some of you listening probably are already at least somewhat familiar with promises.
但我不确定每个人都有很好的概念基础
But I'm not sure everyone has had a very good conceptual grounding in what
承诺真的是，为什么承诺是有用的，
a promise really is, and why a promise is useful,
因为我在开源社区看到了很多关于承诺的争论。
cuz I see an awful lot of arguing about promises in the open source community.
而且他们似乎非常关注关于API的争吵
And they seem to focus an awful lot on bickering about the API for
承诺，并且错过了为什么他们存在的更深层次的观点。
promises, and missing out on the deeper point of why they even exist.
所以对于我们今天将要经历的每个主题，我们的目标是建立
So for each of the topics that we're gonna go through today our goal is to build up
先是概念上的理解，然后在实践中理解我们为什么要做这件事，
a conceptual understanding first and then in practice of why we do the thing,
一旦我们知道为什么要做这件事。
of doing the thing once we know why we do it.
所以我们在和一些代码交谈之前就开始了。
So we're gonna actually start even before we talk with some code.
我们将开始理解一个非常重要的区别
We're gonna start understanding a very important distinction that is often
合并。
conflated.
我们将研究并行性与异步性的概念。
We're gonna look at the notion of parallelism versus asynchronicity.
这实际上是在表达并发的概念。
This is really speaking to the idea of concurrency.
所以我们实际上要深入研究并发的真正含义，具体地说，
So we're actually gonna dig into what concurrency really means, specifically,
它对JavaScript开发人员意味着什么。
what it means to a JavaScript developer.
因为这就是我们做其他事情的动力。
Cuz that is the motivation by which we do all the rest of the things.
然后我们将注意力转向回调，这是最基本的前提
Then we're gonna turn our attention to callbacks, the most fundamental premise
在所有这些中，异步编程的基本单元。
of all of, the fundamental unit of asynchronous programming.
我们真正要看到的是回拨，
And what we're really gonna see is that callbacks,
同时能够表达我们需要的一切。
while capable of expressing everything that we need.
有一些非常显着的缺陷。
Have some very significant deficiencies.
事实上有两个主要缺陷
Two major deficiencies in fact
我会用它来定义回调地狱的概念。
that I would use to define the notion of callback hell.
回叫地狱被扔得太多了，当我说到这个词的时候，大多数人
Callback hell is thrown around an awful lot and most people when I say that term
在他们的脑海中唤起的是，这与压痕有关，
What evokes in their mind is that it has something to do with indentation,
筑巢，诸如此类的事情。
with nesting, things like that.
我要向你们展示的是，回调地狱实际上几乎与
What I'm gonna show you is that callback hell is actually almost nothing to do with
缩进和嵌套。
indentation and nesting.
还有更深层的东西
There's something much deeper,
更重要的是要了解回调地狱。
much more important to understand about callback hell.
所以我们要看看回调，看看它们是如何工作的。
So we're gonna look at callbacks and look at how they work.
首先，我们将与他们进行一些练习，以了解这种情况
First, we'll get some practice with them just to understand that kind of some first
第一人称经历的痛苦，我相信你们都已经有了。
first person experience with the pain of that I'm sure you all have that already.
但接下来我们会看看这些问题是什么给它们起个名字，
But then we're gonna look at what those problems are give them a name,
给那些专业齿轮的问题回叫地狱一个名字。
give those pro gear the problems callback hell a name.
这将是我们试图解决这些问题的动机
And that will be our motivation to why we want to try to solve those problems with
这些高阶模式。
these higher order patterns.
我们将要研究的回调的另一种变体是
Another variation on callbacks that we're going to look at which is kind of
有趣的是，它并没有得到太多的关注。
interesting it is not gotten a lot of attention.
你们中的许多人可能以前甚至没有听说过，但却听到了“砰”的一声。
Many of you may not even heard before but thunks.
雷鸣是我最近甚至自己也有过的一种感觉
Thunks are something that I even just sort of recently myself and
我最近我的意思是在过去的一两年里，发现了这个模式，并意识到，
I recently I mean within the last year or two, discovered this pattern and realized,
哇，我真希望我能在几年前说出这个模式。
wow, I really wish I had been able to articulate that pattern years ago.
因为，实际上它是理解的一个很好的前兆
Because, actually it's a really good precursor to understanding
承诺是关于什么的。
what promises are about.
所以我们会看看thunks，我们会看看为什么它们是这个工具的一部分，
So we'll look at thunks and we'll look at why they are part of that tool,
它们是你应该在工具中心拥有的小工具之一。
they're one of the little tools you should have in your tool center.
对Thunk真正是什么有这样的概念性理解
Having that conceptual understanding of what a thunk really is and
它的有用之处将使我们成为承诺的桥梁。
what it's useful for that will bridge us into promises.
换句话说，thunks有点像没有花哨API的承诺。
In other words, thunks are kinda like promises without the fancy API.
因此，一旦我们得到了thunks的概念基础，就会理解为什么承诺
So once we get the conceptual grounding in thunks will understand why promises
是有用的。
are useful.
我们将查看如何使用承诺的API，我们将获得一些模式
We'll look at the APIs for how to use promises, we'll get some patterns for
一路上每一种模式我们都会重新审视
them all along the way every one of these patterns we're going to be revisiting
一次练习，一次又一次完全相同的练习。
an exercise, the exact same exercise over and over and over again.
然后您将使用以下每一项重新实现该练习的解决方案
And you're gonna re-implement the solution to that exercise using every single one of
这些来自回调的模式一直到目标都是你将成为的
these patterns from callbacks all the way up the goal there being that you will be
完全明白你再也不用担心问题域了
fully understand you don't have to worry about the problem domain anymore you be
充分了解每种模式的利弊。
fully understanding the pros and cons of each of these patterns.
所以这就是我们要去做的事情。
So that's how we'll go about it.
所以我们在看承诺。
So we're looking at promises.
在协同例程中没有好的生成器。
There were no good generators in co-routines.
当我们看到发电机中的承诺时，我们实际上会有
And by the time we've looked at promises in generators we actually will have
建立了两个坚实的解决方案来解决那些主要的召回地狱问题。
a established two solid solutions to those major issues of callback hell.
表示基线的。
That represents the baseline.
如果你准备好不管我的话。
The point at which if you're ready to like tune me out.
我冤枉了你，或者你很无聊，或者其他什么。
I have wronged you or you're bored or whatever.
你必须得到这个角色。
You gotta get this part.
你必须通过承诺和发电机。
You gotta get through the promises and generators.
这是能力的新基线。
That is the new baseline for competency.
异步编程就是理解什么是承诺，
And asynchronous programming is understanding what promises are,
什么是发电机？
what generators are and
为什么两者需要混合在一起来解决回调的问题。
why the two need to be mixed together to solve the issues of callback call.
这是能力的新标准。
That's the new standard for competency.
所以如果你没有从我想做的车间里得到任何东西，那就是真的
So that's really if you get nothing else out of the workshop I wanna make
当然每个人都能做到这一点。
sure everybody gets to that point.
所以我们会花大量的时间来确保我们能达到这一点。
So we'll spend plenty of time making sure we get to that point.
但这还不是全部，因为异步编程还有更多
But that's not all because there's more to asynchronous programming that
这些模式不一定擅长。
those patterns aren't necessarily good at.
有更多的变化。
There are more variations.
我想说的是，
Point that I'm making is,
在我17年的JavaScript生涯中，我从来没有写过很多代码。
I have never once I've written a lot of code in my 17 years in JavaScript.
我从来没有用准确的方法写过一个完整的程序
I've never once written an entire program using exactly
到处都是同样的抽象。
the same abstraction everywhere.
没有一颗银弹。
There is no one silver bullet.
每当有人告诉我X是新的Y，我的BS雷达
Anytime somebody starts to tell me something like X is the new Y, my BS radar
我想，不，它可能不是，事实上，几乎可以肯定它不是。
goes off I'm like no it's probably not, as matter of fact it's almost certainly not.
没有一颗银弹可以取代其他任何东西。
There's no one silver bullet that replaces everything else.
所以我今天教你们的任何东西都不会取代其他任何东西
So nothing that I'm teaching you today is going to be replacing everything else that
我们谈过你应该考虑这些事情而不是所有的战争
we've talked about rather you should consider these things instead of all wars
你仍然可以考虑他们。
you can still should consider them ands.
这是加法。
This is additive.
这些是额外的工具，额外的模式，你可以发展直觉
These are additional tools additional patterns and you can develop instincts for
为什么一种模式更适合于一组特定的问题。
why one pattern is more well suited for a particular set of problems.
我的程序试图在必要时有效地使用这些不同的模式中的每一个。
My programs try to efficiently use each of these different patterns where necessary.
甚至像回调和雷鸣这样的事情也有它们的位置。
Even things like callbacks and thunks have their place.
承诺有自己的位置。
Promises have their place.
发电机有自己的位置。
Generators have their place.
此外，当我们开始处理事件流时，我们会发现承诺
In addition, when we start dealing with event streams we'll find that promises
实际上，当我们开始处理这些问题时，并没有给我们提供一个非常好的解决方案
actually don't really give us a very good solution when we start dealing with
面向事件的编程，我称之为事件反应，反应序列。
event oriented programming, what I call event reactive a reactive sequences.
这也是一个可以观察到的名字。
That's also goes by the name observable.
所以，如果你读过什么，最近有一种说法。
So if you've read anything, there's been a buzz recently.
关于这个可观测概念，有相当多的信息。
There's quite a bit of information out there about this notion of observables.
有一个来自微软的库，叫做RXJS，
There's a library from Microsoft called, RXJS,
可观察模式的最常见实现之一。
one of the most common implementations of the observable pattern.
我将向您展示这些模式，以及它为什么有用。
I'll show you what that patterns about why it's useful.
我们将在实践中将其与可观测的表达式联系起来
We will relate that back to in practice with the expression of observables in
异步库，因为这将更容易
asynchronous library cuz that will be easier for
我们可以玩，而不需要学习一个有数百种方法的巨大图书馆。
us to play with without learning a huge library with hundreds of methods.
所以其中非常小的一部分将使用异步
So a very small subsection of that will play with an asynchronous that I
呼叫反应序列做，基本上相同的事情。
call reactive sequences does,basically the same thing.
所以这是一个更高阶的模式，它将帮助我们，把所有其他的东西
So that's a higher order pattern that will help us, put all the other stuff
我们一起以有趣的方式学习并解决面向事件的编程。
that we've learned together in interesting ways and solve event oriented programming.
面向事件的异步编程。
Event oriented asynchronous programming.
最后，最后一个模式，看的是非常高级的模式。
And finally, the last pattern that will look at very high level pattern.
最近并没有得到太多的关注，但它被称为CSP。
Hasn't gotten a lot of attention recently but it's called CSP.
它代表通信顺序进程。
It's stands for communicating sequential processes.
这并不是一个新的概念，实际上它是在60年代早期发明的，而且
This is not a new concept actually it was invented in the early 60s, and
它是由一些非常聪明的人开发和思考的，他们比我聪明得多。
it was developed and thought about by some really smart people way smarter than I am.
所以我在这里展示的没有什么新的，没有的新信息
So there's nothing new that I'm presenting here no new information that hasn't been
谈论了几十年。
talked about for decades.
但它几乎感觉CSP是在一个重新发现的尖端。
But it almost feels like CSP is on the cusp of a rediscovering.
特别是因为最近我们看到了一些更受欢迎的，
In particular because recently we've seen some more popular,
更多的主流类型语言采用这种模型进行并发。
more mainstream type languages adopt this model for concurrency.
也就是说，Go语言使用CSP模型
Namely the Go language uses the CSP model for
并发性以及闭包和闭包脚本，闭包脚本是桥
concurrency as well as closure and closure script, closure script being the bridge
这将结束浏览器中的JavaScript世界。
that brings closure into the Into the JavaScript world in the browser.
所以越来越多的人开始搬家
So more and more people are starting to move into the Go
编程语言世界，并分为Clojure和ClojureScript。
programming language world and into Clojure and ClojureScript.
他们发现CSP是一个非常强大的模式
And they're discovering that CSP is this really powerful pattern for
管理并发。
managing concurrency.
我听到人们在可观察的方面
And I have heard people on the observable side for
例子告诉我，观察者就是那颗银弹。
example tell me observables are that silver bullet.
您可以使用可观察对象对所有内容进行建模。
You can model everything with an observable.
是啊，有点，也许吧。
Yeah, kind of, maybe.
有些地方真的很好
There are some places that it's really good and
有些地方不是很好。
some places that it's not so good.
然后，我听到人们说，好吧，
And then, I've heard people say, well,
你甚至不需要承诺，因为你可以用CSP频道做任何事情。
you don't even need promises because you can do everything with a CSP channel.
但在有些地方，这是有用的，但在有些地方却并非如此
But there's places where that's useful in places where it's not so
这不是一件全有或全无的事情。
this is not an all or nothing thing.
但CSP从根本上来说是一个相当未被发现，或更不为人知的，
But CSP is a fundamentally rather undiscovered, or rather untalked about,
某种模式。
sort of pattern.
但我有点相信它代表着下一波浪潮。
But I'm kind of convinced that it represents kind of the next next wave.
如果可以观察到大浪，如果它要冲刷我们，
If the big wave is observable, if that's about to wash over us,
后面的是CSP，所以我想要意识到这些事情
the one after it is CSPs, so I wanna be aware of those things and
了解所有这些工具是如何编织在一起的。
understand how all these tools weave together.
到这一步结束时，我们正在进行一些相当有挑战性的练习
By the end of this will be we're working through some rather challenging exercises
试图推动我们的大脑去思考，而不仅仅是一个简单的回调。
trying to push our brains Into thinking way beyond just a simple callback.
所以这就是我们这个工作坊要去的地方。
So that's where we're going with this workshop.
如果事情一开始看起来太简单，
If things seem too simple at the beginning,
我向你保证，到最后他们会有足够的东西来挖你的牙。
I promise you by the end they'll be plenty to be digging your teeth into.